[Music]
today's tutorial is this Dutch fishtail
braid I've seen a lot of people wearing
these on Instagram so I thought I'd do a
tutorial on how to achieve it you'll
probably find you get the best results
if you do this on two-day old hair so
it's perfect if you don't have time to
wash your hair but you need something
stylish doing with it you want to create
a side parting even if you don't
normally wear it on a side parting as
you want the braid to start at the very
top of your head if you've got super
fine hair you might want to apply some
volumizing texture dust to the root and
this is just going to help to plump the
hair up and it will also give it some
extra grip so your braid stays in place
if your hair is not naturally long and
thick like mine then you can apply
extensions to achieve the same look so
I'm going to take a small section of
hair at the front about an inch wide and
about 2 in long then with any regular
fish plat we are working with two
strands so as you can see I've separated
them and we've got our two strands to
start with so to start with we're going
to take a small section from one of the
sections I'm starting at at the back
we're going to cross that underneath the
section we've just taken it from and
pass it to the first section so I'm
doing this nice and slow so hopefully
you can follow along then we're going to
do the same from the front section so
we're taking a small section of
hair passing that underneath the first
section we've taken it from and passing
it to the back section and you should
have something that looks like this so
we've got a crisscross in the middle and
we've just got two sections in our hands
so we're going to repeat the the process
with the back section we're going to
take a small sliver of hair again we're
going to pass that underneath to the
front section but before we move on we
want to pick up another piece of hair
from our head and pass that under as
well so now we're going to start
incorporating hair like we would if we
were doing a regular french
plate so make sure your sections are
nice and clean and put them together so
again we've still only got two sections
of hair but we're crisscrossing them
underneath I'm going to show you again
before I start speeding up so we're
going to take another sliver of hair
from the front section so we're going to
pass that underneath and then we're
going to pick up another section of hair
from the front of the head and also pass
that underneath and that's going to
incorporate to the back section so again
we've still got two
strands and you just want to keep
repeating the process if you've got
particularly tangly hair make sure
you've brushed your hair first just so
it doesn't start becoming a mess it can
take a little bit of practice you want
to hold your strands quite tight so that
when you're incorporating the hair it's
not be com too loose although we're
going to pull the braid apart we want
the structure there first so just keep
working your way down taking a small
section of hair from one of the sections
passing it underneath to the other
section while incorporating a piece of
hair from your head the more you do it
the quicker you'll become at it and
you'll start to see that you're getting
that fish tail look to your braid
[Music]
once you've braided down as far as the
side of your forehead then you want to
start incorporating hair from the other
side so first off take your small sliver
of hair from the back section and
incorporate underneath to our front
section then I put my hand behind my
head and I use my ingots finger to scoop
the hair in a swooping motion from the
front all the way around to the back and
remember you only want to do this around
the top half of the crown because we're
going to be doing this in sections so
we're incorporating that hair underneath
our back section and joining it with our
front section at the front you do the
same as you did before a small section
of hair underneath and join in with our
back section before we move on I like to
pull my braid apart as I go as it can be
really difficult once you've done the
whole thing when you pull on each Loop
you want to pull on the outer half of
the loop that way you're going to get a
nice spread to the plat you're not going
to end up pulling the plat away from the
center so we're not ruining the nice
tight structure we're just loosening the
outer edges and then you want to carry
on working your way down it's up to you
if you want to guide your plat past your
ear or if you want to cover your ear
it's entirely up to you remember every
time you're incorporating hair from that
back section you want to take it from
the opposite side of your head all the
way around the back and then underneath
that back section to the front now very
mind this can make your front section
quite thick so what I like to do is when
I take a sliver of the hair I like to
make it slightly thicker at the front
that way the hair that goes underneath
into the back means that we're balancing
out the thickness of both sections I
hope that makes sense so you just want
to carry on the whole process
incorporating all the hair from one side
to the other until all the hair is in
the
[Music]
plat once you've Incorporated all the
hair from the back of your neck you then
just want to start doing a regular
fishtail braid and then you can start
working up the side of the plat pulling
again on the outer half of the loops as
I mentioned earlier in the tutorial it's
easier to do this as you go that way you
can really loosen the plat the amount
you want you'll find it a lot more
difficult once the braids tight to the
bottom continue down the tail of your
hair just regular fish tail braiding I
don't like to take mine all the way down
I stop about 2/3 of the way down and
then I just use a little elastic band
just to tie it off do the of your
pulling apart before you tie your hair
off that way you've got a little bit
more give at the ends of your hair but
do hold the tail very tight cuz you
don't want to let go otherwise you'll
ruin everything that you've done so I
tie it off with a tiny clear elastic and
then I just wrap a small strand of hair
around the elastic so you can't see it
and then on both sides of my head I just
like to pull out tiny strands of hair
just to give it a soft messy feel and
that is my Dutch fishtail braid complete
it's the perfect look for the spring and
summer and I did to wear at festivals if
you do decide to replicate it please
share it with me on your Instagram or
tweet me you can find the links to those
in my description bar so if you haven't
done so already please click subscribe
you can click on this now and if you've
missed either of my previous tutorials
then you can click on either of these
now and it will take you to those
remember you can follow me on Facebook
Twitter and Instagram bye
[Music]